john i wanted to ask you about
one of the uh confirmation hearings that
are taking place of avril haynes
uh that began yesterday along with a
number of others the secretary of state
the secretary of defense
department of homeland security avril
haynes biden's nominee to be director of
national
intelligence she was obama's top lawyer
on the national security council from
2010 to 2013 and cia deputy director
from
2013 to 15 where she authorized using
drone strikes to carry out targeted
extra
judicial assassinations in 2015
when she was cia deputy director cia
agents illegally hacked
the computers of the senate intelligence
committee to thwart its investigation
into the cia's detention and
interrogation program and he called
torture program
that used torture methods that were
called enhanced interrogation like
waterboarding
she overruled those cia's own inspector
general and failing to discipline the
agents and even awarded them the career
intelligence medal
john kiriakou you are a cia
whistleblower do you know about the
history of avril haynes and what are
your thoughts on
her becoming dni i was frankly very
disappointed when
president-elect biden named avril haynes
as the the dni
there are so many questions that so many
of us have about avril haynes and the
work she did at the white house
as well as at the cia that really have
to be answered
we know that avril haynes at the nsc was
in charge
of of determining whether
it was legal or illegal to place people
on john brennan's kill list
we know that in in almost all cases that
she said it was legal to put these names
on the kill list and people were
subsequently killed
uh by drone uh including american
citizens like anwar
al-laqi and his son they were american
citizens who had never been charged with
a crime
they had never faced their accusers in a
court of law there was no due process
for them
she's never had to answer for that as
you pointed out correctly
she was also the deputy director of the
cia when the cia
under john brennan was hacking into the
senate intelligence committee's
computer systems in order to disrupt the
investigation
uh that led to the senate torture report
and finally another question
that i have that i would like to see uh
her answer
is what her role was exactly
in the redaction of the see the of the
senate intelligence committee's torture
report
remember that report was never released
what was released was a very heavily
redacted
version of the executive summary of that
report so we
we got a very heavily blacked out 500
pages
well there are another 5 000 pages to
that report
that we have never seen
and john kiriakou what about the
situation with julian assange and what
you would hope that the
biden administration might do in
relationship to him
i've been in very close touch uh over
the last couple of weeks with
people around julian and people on his
legal team and we've been trying to read
the tea leaves
relative to the british court's decision
not to extradite him to the united
states
that's being appealed right now and uh
you know you hear things
both ways for example when you read the
the judge's uh ruling uh
until the very end it looks like julian
is just getting
clobbered in this ruling the judge
essentially agreed with everything that
the justice department said and then at
the very end of the ruling
said that because julian uh suffers from
depression
and is suicidal that sending him to the
united states where he would be subject
to solitary confinement which the un has
declared to be a form of torture
would push him over the edge so the
ruling was great the reasoning leading
up to the ruling was
not so great and now the justice
department
is appealing the rumor that i heard
was that perhaps the biden people
reached out to the british and said
look we wouldn't be terribly upset if
this thing were to just go away
uh and then we got the great ruling well
now it's being appealed so what happens
if he loses the appeal
even if he wins the appeal if there's no
pardon
or commutation and so far there isn't
what's to keep the british from
expelling him to australia
and then the justice department just
asking the australians to extradite him
all over again
so really the only the only way we can
end this whole thing for julian
is is uh through a presidential action
it has to be
a pardon or a commutation and people can
go to democracynow.org to
see the um speech of niels melzer who
is the u.n special rapporteur on torture
and other in cruel
inhuman or degrading treatment or
punishment he visited
julian assange at the belmarsh prison
finally john kiriakou what happens to
this money
the millions of dollars they are raking
in
is it giuliani is it going some bank
account for trump when he leaves like
the
hundreds of millions of dollars he
raised after the election
um lying about election fraud uh
who tracks this money ah
that's a good question and the answer is
that nobody tracks this money
this money goes directly into the
pockets of the lobbyists and the lawyers
who charged it you know there was a
terrific article in the new york times
about
six months ago talking about rudy
giuliani's fourth divorce
and in the course of discovery the new
york times
uh learned that rudy is a member of
16 different country clubs
and he told the court that he needs
seven million dollars a year to maintain
his current lifestyle
and to pay his dues at 16 separate
country clubs
and so how's he going to do that he's
going to do it by gouging
as many people as he possibly can rudy's
not a stupid guy
he knew that the moment that donald
trump walked out of the white house
to get on that plane and fly back to
florida that his career was
finished because now nobody is going to
pay rudy giuliani
anything he's done